Peter McNulty

Fordyce, North Foreland Avenue | Broadstairs, Kent, CT10 3QR | Phone: 07734392094 | E-Mail: petemc121@gmail.com Github: https://github.com/Petemc121 | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/peter-mcnulty-86b007142/ Portfolio: https://roamingrolls.com/pete-programmes/

WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPER | FRONT END DEVELOPER | CHEMIST

PROFILE SUMMARY

Dedicated and innovative Front End Developer with extensive experience in using Web Technologies like JavaScript, PHP, C, MySQL, React, Bootstrap, Webpack, and Wordpress that follows Web Standards. Successfully managing all facets of site development, which includes architecture, site deployment, and client management. Experienced in making webpage cross-browser compatible and involved in Analysis, Design, Development, Testing, and Implementation of Applications, Application Maintenance, and Project Deliverables. Enjoy taking on complex and challenging tasks and love bringing designs to life and creating beautiful, usable experiences for all users.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF SUSSEX | Master of chemistry (1:1)2012 - 2016DANE COURT GRAMMAR SCHOOL | GCSE2005 - 2012

COMPETENT SKILLS

- Front End Development
- Responsive Web Design
- Search Engine Optimisation
- Google Analytics
- Debugging and Troubleshooting
- Teamwork & Leadership Skills
- Communication Skills
- Customer Service
- Organizational Skills

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

Languages: JavaScript, PHP, C, MySQL Frameworks: React, Bootstrap, Webpack CMS: Wordpress

NOTABLE PROJECTS

Roaming Rolls - A BJJ gym database website

Link: https://www.roamingrolls.com/ | Github Link: https://github.com/Petemc121/RoamingRolls

- Developed front for the entire website using HTML and CSS. Gets continually updated as I learn new skills to improve the UI
 and user experience on the website.
- Test the website on multiple browsers with their old as well as latest release. Maintain and update the codebase as well as incorporate new, rich interactive experiences into the website.
- Provided continued maintenance and development of bug fixes and patch sets for the website. Utilized new software methodologies to be able to adapt to changes in requirements quickly.
- Developed high-performance and reusable front-end code in a timely and high quality manner while ensuring a consistent look and feel.

BJJ Techniques Log - A web-app built for logging BJJ techniques

Link: https://petemc121.github.io/BJJ-techniques-log/ | Github Link: https://github.com/Petemc121/BJJ-techniques-log/

- Worked on analysis, design, development and implementation of web applications using React, Bootstrap, and JavaScript.
- Setup and maintained the databases in MySQL and leveraged industry expertise, creative mentality, and strong interpersonal skills to produce complex designs for diverse audiences.
- Coded JavaScript for page functionality and Pop up Screens and used PHP to make dropdown menus on pages and display part of a page.
- Developed user interface using Bootstrap framework to simplify the complexities of the application. Designed a MySQL database to connect the front end and the back end of the web application.

Simple Restaurant Page - A simple restaurant page built using web pack and nodeJS modules.

Github Link: https://github.com/Petemc121/restaurant-page-webpack

- Developed a single-page website using web pack and nodeJS. Utilized highly modularized and advanced object-oriented design to ensure ease of maintenance.
- Demonstrated a mature understanding of the entire development process, including design, specification, documentation, implementation, and testing.
- Prioritized and fixed the design problems and taking the initiative to implement new features based on feedback from users.
- Corrected the errors by making appropriate changes and rechecking the program to ensure that the desired results are produced.

Covid Stats Page - A web page designed to list Covid statistics using APIs, with basic animation practice. Github link: https://github.com/Petemc121/Corona-statistics-app

- Developed a website using HTML, MySQL, APIs, with basic animation practice. Developed the various pages and its architecture in accordance with UI specs.
- Involved in requirements and analysis: understanding the requirements of the client and the flow of the website. Involved with bug fixing on functionality, performance and designing issues with HTML, MySQL, and C.
- Determined the sources of web page or server problems, and taking action to correct such problems. Reviewed or updated web page content or links in a timely manner, using appropriate tools.
- Used Google Analytics to monitor and track analytics on websites to analyse positive and negative aspects of the website's user experience.

Korean Name Translator - a simple web app designed to convert Korean character names to romanic names using an API and JS code

Github Link: https://github.com/Petemc121/Korean-name-translator

- Performed requirement analysis, design, development, testing, maintenance and deployment of the web application. Planned, managed, and executed the implementation of new functionality from the ground up.
- Ensured application's ease-of-use, accuracy, and user satisfaction by assessing needs, research, and developing specifications/guidelines.
- Diagnosed and resolved application errors, generated comprehensive test plans and performed root cause analysis on application problems.

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

Nippon Paint Automotive Industries	
Development Chemist	
East Kent	May 2012 - Present
EBP support staff	
Deliveroo	May 2016 - Sep 2016
Courier	
Masters Research Project	2015 - 2016
Generation of nanostructured metal oxide semiconductors for solar energy harvesting	
University of Sussex Employment (Summers)	2015 - 2016
Spectroscopy In a Suitcase (SIAS)	
Summer Research Placement	Jun 2015 - Jul 2015
Montezumas Chocolate Shop	
Sales Assistant	
The New Mala Tandoori	Jul 2012 - Aug 2012
Courier	
The Kent Festival of Science	2009 - 2011
Show Assistant/Guide	

OTHER INTERESTS AND SKILLS

- Proficient with programmes such as Word, Excel, Mandalay and X'pert HighScore Plus.
- Eight years' experience in climbing, three of which competitively in events such as the SIBL (Southern Indoor Bouldering League), the BMC (British Mountaineering Council) youth climbing series and the BLCCs (British Lead Climbing Championships).
- Recently returned from seven months of travelling around South East Asia, which involved teaching English in Myanmar.
- Seven years' experience with playing drums and five years with guitar.
- In possession of a full driver's license.

REFERENCE

Available Upon Request